englandrugby.com 2018-12-23

# RFU - About the RFU

###  Data Protection

As the national governing body for rugby union in England and operator of Twickenham Stadium, the RFU processes a large amount of personal data, including data from fans, participants and third parties.  
Much of this data is used in order to safeguard the game for all participants.

The RFU wants to use this data in a way which is fair and transparent.   
The two Privacy Notices available below explain what data is used and why.

  * The Regulatory and Governance Privacy Notice sets out what data is used and why for regulatory and governance reasons as a result of the RFU’s role as national governing body. 
  * The England Rugby Privacy Notice sets out what data is used and why for fans and visitors to Twickenham Stadium and other RFU events.

The Game Management System Privacy Notice also explains how the RFU, clubs, constituent bodies and referee societies use data entered into the Game Management System.

Use of www.englandrugby.com and other websites operated by the RFU is subject to our [cookie policy](https://www.englandrugby.com/about-the-rfu/privacy-policy/#cookies).

The General Data Protection Regulation(GDPR) will also apply to clubs, constituent bodies and referee societies.  
The RFU has provided guidance for the game in the form of a GDPR toolkit and associated documents.  
These can be found in the [GDPR for rugby clubs section](https://www.englandrugby.com/governance/club-support/gdpr/).

The GDPR gives individuals a number of rights in relation to their data. Further detail is set out in the Privacy Notices above. If you would like to make a Subject Access Request in respect of data held by the RFU, please fill in this form and send it either by email to [legal@rfu.com](mailto:legal@rfu.com) or by post to The Data Protection Officer, Rugby Football Union, Rugby House, Twickenham Stadium, Twickenham TW2 7BA. Please note that if you would like to make a Subject Access Request in respect of data held by a club, constituent body, referee society, World Rugby or another rugby body, you will need to contact that body directly.

### Cookies

#### Use of Cookies on our website

We use cookies to collect information about your online preference. Cookies are small pieces of information sent by a web server to a web browser which allows the server to uniquely identify the browser on each page. We may use some or all of the following categories of cookies on our website: 

#### Strictly Necessary Cookies

These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the website and use its features. Without these cookies, services you have asked for such as remembering your login details or shopping basket items cannot be provided.

#### Performance Cookies

These cookies collect anonymous information on how people use our Website. For example, we use Google Analytics cookies to help us understand how customers arrive at our site, browse or use our site and highlight areas where we can improve areas such as navigation, shopping experience and marketing campaigns. The data stored by these cookies never shows personal details from which your individual identity can be established.

#### Functionality Cookies

These cookies remember choices you make such as the country you visit our website from, language and search parameters such as size, colour or product line. These can then be used to provide you with an experience more appropriate to your selections and to make the visits more tailored and pleasant. The information these cookies collect may be anonymised and they cannot track your browsing activity on other websites.

#### Targeting cookies or advertising cookies

These cookies collect information about your browsing habits in order to make advertising more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advert as well as help measure the effectiveness of an advertising campaign. The cookies are usually placed by third party advertising networks. They remember the websites you visit and that information is shared with other parties such as advertisers. For example, we use third party companies to provide you with more personalised adverts when visiting other websites.

#### Social Media Cookies

These cookies allow you to share what you’ve been doing on the website on social media such as Facebook and Twitter. These cookies are not within our control. Please refer to the respective privacy policies for how their cookies work.

#### Use of Web Beacons

Some of our Web pages may contain electronic images known as Web beacons that allow us to count users who have visited these pages. Web beacons collect only limited information which including a cookie number, time and date of a page view, and a description of the page on which the Web beacon resides. We may also carry web beacons placed by third party advertisers. These beacons do not carry any personally identifiable information and are only used to track the effectiveness of a particular campaign. 

#### Managing Cookies

If you want to delete any cookies that are already on your computer, please refer to the help and support area on your internet browser for instructions on how to locate the file or directory that stores cookies.

Please note that by deleting our cookies or disabling future cookies you may not be able to access certain areas or features of our site.

To find out more about cookies please see [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) which contains further information about behavioural advertising and online privacy.
